=Stitching Life and Death=
=خياطة الحياة والموت=
=Episode 8=
=الحلقة 8=
One incense before the Mountain God's altar,
بخور واحد أمام مذبح إله الجبل،
confessing past wrongs to the great deity.
الاعتراف بالأخطاء الماضية للإله العظيم.
Youth is prone to folly.
الشباب عرضة للحمق.
May the celestial lords be lenient.
ليكن الأسياد السماويون متساهلين.
Get up.
انهض.
Why are you still standing there?
لماذا ما زلت واقفًا هناك؟
Hurry and help my son up!
أسرع وساعد ابني على النهوض!
Magistrate.
قاضي الحافظة.
Mr. Ma.
السيد ما.
The ritual
الطقوس
is mostly completed.
تمت بشكل كبير.
Mostly?
بشكل كبير؟
The affairs of the underworld have been settled.
تمت تسوية أمور العالم السفلي.
However, he needs to do good deeds and accumulate good karma.
ومع ذلك، يحتاج إلى القيام بأعمال جيدة وتراكم الكارما الجيدة.
It all depends on you whether to build bridges
كل شيء يعتمد عليك سواء لبناء الجسور
or repair the roads.
أو إصلاح الطرق.
Mr. Ma, please wait.
السيد ما، من فضلك انتظر.
It must've been tough on you.
لابد أنه كان صعبًا عليك.
Sorry for the trouble.
آسف على الإزعاج.
Son.
ابني.
Do you feel better?
هل تشعر بتحسن؟
Master,
سيدي،
how did you find out
كيف اكتشفت
about Ms. Ruyi's disappearance?
اختفاء السيدة رويي؟
Didn't Master Song say this himself?
ألم يقل السيد سونغ هذا بنفسه؟
He has interviewed many people
لقد أجرى مقابلات مع العديد من الناس
to collect evidence of their crimes.
لجمع الأدلة على جرائمهم.
Mr. Ma.
السيد ما.
Master Song.
السيد سونغ.
So, Ms. Lichun was the one who told you about it.
إذن، السيدة لي تشون هي التي أخبرتك بذلك.
Mr. Ma, this is Ruyi's mother.
السيد ما، هذه والدة رويي.
Thank you, Mr. Ma.
شكراً لك، سيد ما.
My daughter's body has been finally located.
تم العثور على جثة ابنتي أخيراً.
Now, I can lay her to rest.
الآن، يمكنني أن أدفنها بسلام.
Please get up.
من فضلك، انهض.
Qiu.
تشيو.
Master.
سيدي.
Madam, you should take this first.
سيدتي، يجب أن تأخذي هذا أولاً.
Take it as a compensation for Ruyi and your family.
خذيها كتعويض عن رويي وعائلتك.
This...
هذا...
Here.
هنا.
Take it.
خذيها.
What does she mean by that?
ماذا تعني بذلك؟
Ms. Lichun said
قالت السيدة لي تشون
everyone out there is cursing you out.
الجميع هناك يلعنونك.
They said you cured Zhao Tai
قالوا أنك شفيت تشاو تاي.
for money's sake.
من أجل المال.
So, you were a mute, huh?
إذن، كنت أخرس، أليس كذلك؟
No wonder you never spoke.
لا عجب أنك لم تتكلم أبداً.
Qiu.
تشيو.
Must your mouth always run unchecked?
هل يجب أن يكون لسانك دائمًا بلا ضوابط؟
Ms. Lichun, in this world, you have nothing to fear if your conscience is clear.
سيدة لي تشون، في هذا العالم، ليس لديك ما تخافين منه إذا كان ضميرك نقيًا.
It doesn't matter.
لا يهم.
Madam, you don't need to worry either.
سيدتي، لا تحتاجين للقلق أيضًا.
Master Song and I
السيد سونغ وأنا
will definitely uphold justice for Ms. Ruyi.
سنحافظ بالتأكيد على العدالة للسيدة رويي.
I know.
أعلم.
Master Song already told me.
السيد سونغ أخبرني بالفعل.
What does she mean by that?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
Ms. Lichun said
قالت السيدة لي تشون
you were cute.
كنت لطيفًا.
You're making me embarrassed here.
أنت تجعلني أشعر بالإحراج هنا.
By the way, Master Song...
بالمناسبة، سيد سونغ...
Dad, do you truly intend to build bridges and repair the roads?
أبي، هل تنوي حقًا بناء الجسور وإصلاح الطرق؟
Of course.
بالطبع.
It's a waste of money and energy, you know?
إنه إهدار للمال والطاقة، أتعلم؟
Mr. Zhao, you may not know.
سيد تشاو، قد لا تعلم.
When Magistrate Zhao takes on public welfare projects,
عندما يتولى قاضي الحافظة تشاو مشاريع الرفاهية العامة،
he always lines his pockets first.
دائمًا ما يملأ جيوبه أولاً.
If you wish to make money, repair the roads.
إذا كنت ترغب في كسب المال، قم بإصلاح الطرق.
Once the roads are repaired,
بمجرد إصلاح الطرق،
we'll have plenty of money.
سيكون لدينا الكثير من المال.
Mr. Zhao.
السيد تشاو.
I threw up a lot just two days ago.
لقد تقيأت كثيرًا قبل يومين فقط.
I quit drinking since then.
توقفت عن الشرب منذ ذلك الحين.
Don't let him drink that much.
لا تدعه يشرب كثيرًا.
Son, you'll take over my position
يا بني، ستتولى منصبي
sooner or later.
عاجلاً أم آجلاً.
Let me tell you how to repair roads.
دعني أخبرك كيف تصلح الطرق.
When you repair them,
عندما تصلحها،
you mustn't repair them completely.
يجب ألا تصلحها بالكامل.
You have to cut corners.
عليك أن تختصر.
Won't the roads break down again?
ألن تتعطل الطرق مرة أخرى؟
We can repair them again after that.
يمكننا إصلاحها مرة أخرى بعد ذلك.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
Better to pave 10,000 miles of road...
من الأفضل تمهيد 10,000 ميل من الطريق...
Than to read 10,000 books.
من قراءة 10,000 كتاب.
I'm sure my son is this intelligent
أنا متأكد أن ابني ذكي بهذا الشكل
because he inherited my genes.
لأنه ورث جيناتي.
He's talented.
إنه موهوب.
He's a prodigy.
إنه معجزة.
Son,
ابني،
come.
تعال.
You guys can go ahead.
يمكنكم المضي قدماً.
Here it comes.
ها هو يأتي.
Fresh pork for sale.
لحم خنزير طازج للبيع.
Fish for sale!
سمك للبيع!
Fresh fish for sale!
سمك طازج للبيع!
Mister.
سيدي.
I'm not selling it to you. Go away.
لن أبيعها لك. اذهب بعيدًا.
- Hurry and leave. - What do you mean by this?
- أسرع واغادر. - ماذا تقصد بهذا؟
I don't sell my things to guys who are in cahoots with the villains.
لا أبيع أشيائي للأشخاص الذين يتعاونون مع الأشرار.
Explain yourself.
اشرح نفسك.
Who's in cahoots with the villains?
من يتعاون مع الأشرار؟
You and your master, Ma San.
أنت وسيدك، ما سان.
Zhao Tai is a despicable scum who has committed atrocious deeds.
تشاو تاي هو نذل حقير ارتكب أعمالًا شنيعة.
Now that he's finally going to die,
الآن بعد أن سيموت أخيرًا،
you guys actually went to rescue him.
أنتم ذهبتم لإنقاذه.
Now, you want to buy fish from me?
الآن، تريدون شراء السمك مني؟
Guys, listen.
يا رفاق، استمعوا.
He wants to have fish. What should he do?
يريد الحصول على سمك. ماذا يجب أن يفعل؟
- Catch them himself.
- يصطادها بنفسه.
Am I right?
هل أنا محق؟
Did you hear that?
هل سمعت ذلك؟
Go and catch them yourself.
اذهب واصطادها بنفسك.
- That's right. - Precisely.
- هذا صحيح. - بالضبط.
You want vegetables?
تريد خضروات؟
Go and plant them yourself.
اذهب وازرعها بنفسك.
You want meat?
تريد لحم؟
Rear them yourself.
ربها بنفسك.
Leave.
غادر.
I finally understand now.
أخيرًا فهمت الآن.
What's wrong?
ما الأمر؟
You guys knew that Zhao Tai was a despicable scum, huh?
كنتم تعلمون أن تشاو تاي كان حقيرًا، أليس كذلك؟
But why did all of you keep quiet
لكن لماذا التزمتم جميعًا الصمت
when Master Song approached you all?
عندما اقترب منكم السيد سونغ؟
You think I'm easy to bully because I'm an orphan, huh?
تعتقدون أنني سهل التنمر لأنني يتيم، أليس كذلك؟
Don't sell anything to the Zhao family, then!
لا تبيعوا أي شيء لعائلة تشاو إذن!
Just starve them to death!
اجعلوهم يموتون جوعًا!
I didn't want to criticize you guys initially.
لم أكن أرغب في انتقادكم في البداية.
But you guys are too full of yourselves.
لكنكم مغرورون جدًا.
I'm sure you know how timid you were when we needed you the most.
أنا متأكد من أنكم تعرفون مدى جبنكم عندما كنا بحاجة إليكم أكثر.
I'll say this.
سأقول هذا.
I won't spend a dime here
لن أنفق فلسًا واحدًا هنا
as long as that bastard roams free!
طالما أن ذلك الوغد يتجول بحرية!
Cowards.
جبناء.
You and your sharp tongue.
أنت ولسانك الحاد.
Qiu.
تشيو.
Time to eat.
حان وقت الطعام.
Qiu?
تشيو؟
Stop looking. Just a simple meal is fine.
توقف عن النظر. وجبة بسيطة تكفي.
Come and eat.
تعال وتناول الطعام.
Master.
سيدي.
Why don't you buy the groceries tomorrow?
لماذا لا تشتري البقالة غدًا؟
Maybe they'll sell it to you.
ربما سيبيعونها لك.
You're as blunt as ever.
أنت صريح كما كنت دائمًا.
What?
ماذا؟
You think I can do everything
تعتقد أنني أستطيع فعل كل شيء
that you cannot?
الذي لا تستطيع فعله؟
I'm just angry.
أنا فقط غاضب.
What did I teach you usually?
ماذا علمتك عادة؟
Just do good deeds
فقط قم بالأعمال الصالحة
and don't question what lies ahead.
ولا تسأل عما ينتظرك.
You cannot control other people's mouths.
لا يمكنك التحكم في أفواه الآخرين.
They simply don't know what's best for them. They even told you off.
هم ببساطة لا يعرفون ما هو الأفضل لهم. لقد وبخوك حتى.
I was angry at that.
كنت غاضبًا من ذلك.
You said the people represent the heavens.
قلت إن الناس يمثلون السماء.
That doesn't give them the right to change whenever they like.
هذا لا يمنحهم الحق في التغيير متى شاءوا.
Silly boy, that's enough.
يا فتى أحمق، هذا يكفي.
By the way,
بالمناسبة،
do not say that you're an orphan in the future.
لا تقل أنك يتيم في المستقبل.
I'm here, aren't I?
أنا هنا، أليس كذلك؟
Don't say such inauspicious things.
لا تقل مثل هذه الأشياء المشؤومة.
Here.
ها هو.
I kept a bowl of meat for you.
احتفظت لك بوعاء من اللحم.
Eat up.
كُل.
Why are you staring at it?
لماذا تحدق فيه؟
Thank you, Master.
شكراً، سيدي.
Dad.
أبي.
Ma San knows a lot about us.
ما سان يعرف الكثير عنا.
Will he rat us out?
هل سيشي بنا؟
The fewer people know about this,
كلما قل عدد الأشخاص الذين يعرفون عن هذا،
the better.
كان ذلك أفضل.
The more people know,
كلما زاد عدد الأشخاص الذين يعرفون،
the bigger the trouble.
كلما زادت المشاكل.
I'm on your side.
أنا في صفك.
Son,
ابني،
this is my longtime partner.
هذا هو شريكي منذ فترة طويلة.
We have great chemistry.
لدينا كيمياء رائعة.
You have to call her Madam.
عليك أن تناديها عمة.
You can have fun all you like.
يمكنك الاستمتاع كما تشاء.
But if she's pregnant, you have to make her go for an abortion.
لكن إذا كانت حاملاً، عليك أن تجعلها تذهب للإجهاض.
Yeah.
نعم.
I know that.
أعلم ذلك.
You guys are here at this hour?
أنتم هنا في هذا الوقت؟
We're here to see a criminal
نحن هنا لرؤية مجرم
under Magistrate Zhao's order.
بأمر من قاضي المحافظة تشاو.
Open it.
افتحه.
Don't say that I'm not giving you a chance here.
لا تقل أنني لا أعطيك فرصة هنا.
Do a good job,
قم بعمل جيد،
and you'll earn yourself the best chance there is.
وستحصل على أفضل فرصة ممكنة.
I'm a hitman.
أنا قاتل مأجور.
I never ask my targets for their names.
أنا لا أسأل أهدافي عن أسمائهم أبداً.
Likewise, they don't know my name either.
وبالمثل، هم لا يعرفون اسمي أيضاً.